buggyandbuddy.com 2019-04-08

# Privacy - Buggy and Buddy

Here at Buggy and Buddy we value and protect your privacy.

This policy explains when and why we collect information about you, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

We may change this policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. By using our website, you’re agreeing to be bound by this policy.

Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to chelsey@buggyandbuddy.com.

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Buggy and Buddy collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a “User”) of the https://buggyandbuddy.com website (“Site”). This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by Buggy and Buddy.

### Who are we?

Buggy and Buddy  is an online parenting and educational site founded in 2012 by Chelsey Marashian. We share crafts, learning activities, play ideas, printable, and parenting tips for you and your children and students. We are based in the United States, but have contributing authors from around the world.

### How we Collect Information About You

Information is collected via log files, cookies, leaving comments on the site, or subscribing to our newsletter.

### What Information do we Collect About You

We collect information on your name, email address, website (if you leave this in a comment), IP address and the pages that you visited and when you visited them on the site.

We only collect your name and email address from you when you subscribe to our newsletter or to receive email updates.

Buggy and Buddy collects and uses Users personal information for the following purposes:

  * _To send periodic emails:  _If User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include Buggy and Buddy news, updates, products created by Buggy and Buddy and/or contributing authors, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email or User may contact us via our Site.

### How and Why we Track your Visit

Like most websites around the world we use Google Analytics (GA) to process information about the number of visitors on our site, and their behavior.

We use this information to record the number of people using Buggy and Buddy and to better understand where you discover our site (from social media, Google or another site) and how you use it as well as to see how people move throughout the site.

GA records your approximate location down to town level, the type device you are using e.g. Mobile or Table, Name of device e.g. iPad or Samsung Galazy etc…, operating system e.g. Windows 10 or iOS and browser e.g. Firefox or Chrome none of this data can be used to identify you.

Google does record your IP address however, we don’t have access to this information and it modifies it so that you can not be identified specifically just the area that you are in.

### Google Analytics Demographics

We are committed to ensuring that our website contains content that is valuable and useful to our readers.

To help us with this we have implemented the Google analytics demographics and interest reporting features on our website.

These tools allow us to review anonymous data regarding the gender, age and interests of website visitors and adapt our website content to better reflect their needs.

Although this information is collected through your Google ad settings, it is not provided to us in a personally-identifiable format. This means we cannot identify what information is about you, and we will not try to figure it out.

You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customise Google Display Network ads using the [Google Ad settings](https://adssettings.google.ca/anonymous?sig=ACi0TCim925cB07-7cpwU1t82Zih-cyZJ-z258Rhs2_ob_VD9-KN0PF7SNjosxPqWAnMkL5o3KkIzcaiKhInpLNrtrjGb3FOZ2AF3COImtlEVfU_oOnno0I&hl=en) or through the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

To do this Google Analytics uses a “cookie” on your machine read more about Cookies below.

### Leaving a Comment on our Site

We at Buggy and Buddy love to hear from you- if you tried an activity or any tips you may have so we give you the option of leaving a comment.

To leave a comment you may leave it anonymously or leave a name, email address, website and comment.

We only use this information to identify you as the comment maker and do not pass this on to any third party.

Your email address will never be shown in the comment section of the site.

Your details will remain in the database unless we remove it or the article is removed from the site.

You may request that we delete the comment and remove you details at any time. Please email us at chelsey@buggyandbuddy.com to ask for this to be carried out.

If you are under 16 you must obtain your parents permission before leaving a comment.

**IMPORTANT: In your comment you should avoid leaving information of a personal nature and it is recommended that you do this on any website you comment on.**

### Subscriber Newsletter

If you choose to join one of our regular newsletters via a [sign up form on BuggyandBuddy](https://landing.mailerlite.com/webforms/landing/g2q8y6) then you email address is required so that you can be sent the emails. We also ask for your First Name although this isn’t required so that we may address you personal in our weekly email.

Your data is collected and then passed to our Email Service Provider [MailerLite](https://www.mailerlite.com/).

You may unsubscribe at any time from our newsletters using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email.

Within the Email Service Provider we use tags to track the pages that you visit and actions that you take within the emails so that we can provide a more personalised email service to you.

We send emails 1 – 3 times a week and with our tracking try and make these as relevant to you as possible. From time to time we may include promotions for products.

Details that we hold including your name, email address and where you have visited will never be passed onto a Third Party.

### When you purchase from The Buggy and Buddy Shop

If you have made a purchase from the [Buggy and Buddy Shop](https://buggyandbuddy.com/category/shop/) then you details are stored either by our store database for products we have produced and you can download there or via a Third Party either Send Owl for our products or one of the affiliate product owners e.g. Nurturestore, STEAM Kids etc.

We ask for 3 pieces of information for downloads direct from our store – country (to apply EU VAT if necessary), First Name and Email Address.

Products sold via affiliates each collect and retain their own data we do not have access to your name or email address as part of this.

Please see their privacy and data protection policies for more information on how they collect and process your personal data.

### Advertisements on Buggy and Buddy

We use third party advertisements on Buggy and Buddy to support our site.

  * Google Double Click
  * Ad Thrive

Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.

This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

**Information About Adthrive Advertisements**

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

**For European Economic Area Residents**

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at [info@adthrive.com](mailto:info@adthrive.com). If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

### Do We Use Cookies?

Cookies are the little pieces of code that we use to track your use of our site and provide the best possible experience for you.

Specifically we use them for

  * Our commenting system so that you don’t have to always enter you details
  * Collect data as part of Google Analytics so that we can see who has visited our website

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in your browser.

However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on  buggyandbuddy.com.
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to buggyandbuddy.com and other sites on the Internet.
  * You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

Users may find advertising or other content on our Site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website’s own terms and policies.

### **Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### **California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

### **Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

### **Online Privacy Policy Only**

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

### **Your Consent**

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy and terms and conditions. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

### **Changes to our Privacy Policy**

Buggy and Buddy has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

This policy was last modified on April 30, 2018

### **Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

https://buggyandbuddy.com or chelsey@buggyandbuddy.com

**Notice Regarding Online Behavioral Advertising**  
We allow third party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information  
when you visit our Web site.  These companies may use non-personally identifiable information  
(e.g. click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked  
or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide  
advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you.  These  
companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information.  To learn  
more about this behavioral advertising practice visit the NAI at [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).  To  
opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>.
